搞什么
What the hell?
飓风艾丽西娅即将登陆
...Alicia's arrival is imminent,
目前正向西行进
currently traveling west--
风速即将达到75英里
...approaching 75 miles per hour,
并预计将在
expected to exceed that,
明天凌晨登陆前  突破这一速度
before reaching shore sometime late tomorrow morning.
有报道称  石油公司用直升机
Reports of oil company employees
疏散了飓风行进路线上的
being evacuated by helicopter
海上钻井平台工作人员
from offshore rigs in the path of the storm
这消息加剧了公众的恐慌情绪
have punctuated the fear and trepidation that's felt by many.
先进计算机可能...
Advanced computer probability...
等等  等等
Hold on, wait. Wait.
-怎么了  -这些...
- What's wrong? - Where did you--
这些伤疤到底哪来的
how did you get these?
别骗我
Really?
我上高中的时候
I was in high school.
攒了好久的钱
I'd been saving up money for a long time.
暑期打工什么的
Summer jobs and everything.
我买了辆64年的雪佛兰
And I bought a '64 Chevy Nova.
明黄色  一眼就看中了
Bright yellow, love at first sight.
拿到车的那天  我带几个朋友出去兜风
The day I got it, I took some friends out.
当时是二月中旬  天气很冷  非常冷
And it was mid-February and cold. I mean, bitter cold.
路上结了冰  那种晚上不该出去的
Ice on the roads. No one should've been out that night.
等等
Hold on.
是真的吗
Is this true?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你在骗我
You're lying to me.
好吧
Okay.
天啊
Oh, my God.
真相是...天呐  这可真丢人
The truth is-- God, this is embarrassing.
我小时候有个朋友
When I was a kid, I had a buddy
住在农圃道上
who lived out on this farm road
有座很老旧的磨坊
and there was this mill rusted to hell.
一天我挑衅他  说"迈克..."
One day I dared him. I said, "Mike"--
天啊  别说了
Oh, my God. Stop.
这又是谎话吗
Is this another lie?
说真的  你问这干吗  卡梅伦
Why do you care, Cameron? I mean, honestly.
别敷衍我  只是想问问
Stop handling me. It's just a question.
你为什么在乎答案呢
But why do you care about the answer?
你真是一张嘴就坏事
You are too screwed up for words.
就因为我不想在床上给你讲悲伤往事吗
Because I don't want to tell sad stories in bed with you?
-我们的关系怎么变成这样了  -什么"关系"
- When did this become that? - What's "This"?
我们的老规矩  你有需要的时候就过来
Our routine? You come over whenever, I don't know, you need to,
我也很愿意满足你
and I'm happy to oblige.
现在你却突然气我
Now all of a sudden you're getting pissed
不肯跟你玩过家家
'cause I don't want to play house.
别犯浑  只是个问题
Don't do that. It's just a question.
规矩可是你定的
You designed the routine.
这招现在不好使了
Well, it's no longer doing anything for me.
变无聊了
This has gotten boring.
你想走随时可以走
You're free to leave whenever you like.
-你变无聊了  -我说过了
- You have gotten boring. - Like I said.
-你想要建议吗  乔  -不是很想
- You want a piece of advice, Joe? - Not really.
你这一套  是挺吸引人的
Your whole thing, it attracts people,
但不足以留住他们
but it won't keep them around.
真诚才能鼓舞人心
Authenticity is what inspires people.
如果你想成为领袖
If you want to lead people,
就得让人们看到真实的你
you have to show them who you really are.
不然的话
Otherwise,
你只是绣金花的枕头
you're just a thousand-dollar suit with nothing inside.
谁都不会在乎你
No one gives a shit.
几点了
What time is it?
继续睡吧  很晚了
Go back to sleep. It's late.
你满身酒气
Mm, you smell like beer.
我好爱你
I love you so much.
戈登
Gordon.
你太美了
You're so beautiful.
别这样  我要睡觉
Stop it. I have to sleep.
我停不下来
I can't.
我明天还有很多事情  我得去拿蛋糕
I have so much tomorrow. I have to pick up the cake.
那家店6点就关门  我得上班前过去
And I have to do it before work 'cause they close at 6:00.
真可怜
You poor lady.
琼妮最近迷上了椰菜娃娃
And Joanie's become fixated on this Cabbage Patch Doll
还是椰菜仔什么的
or Kid or whatever.
一提起那个  她激动得都哭了
She got so worked up talking about it she started crying...
满脸狂热
tears of mania.
什么东西来着
What is it?
一个玩偶
It's a doll.
就是那种毛公仔
It's a stuffed baby.
我去买一个
I'll get it.
-什么  -我会去买的
- What? - I'm getting it.
戈登·克拉克来拯救你了
Gordon Clark to the rescue.
天哪  真的吗  那真是太棒了
Oh, my God, really? That would be amazing.
别操心了
Don't give it another thought.
快睡吧  小醉鬼
Oh, go to sleep, drunky.
给你个赠券  马上要下暴雨了
Rain check. Big storm's supposed to be coming in.
谢了
Thanks.
昨天晚上的演出怎么样
How was your show last night?
我的吉他着火了
My amp caught on fire.
估计是最精彩的部分了
Probably the best part.
我以为你会来的  你去哪了
I thought you'd be there. Where were you?
出去了
Out.
那是什么
What is that?
《巨洞冒险》的改进版本
Modified version of "Adventure."
我为你做的
I made it for you.
只是图个乐子而已
A stupid thing I did for fun.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
你去上班吗  我载你一程
You going to work? I'll give you a ride.
"天才降临于世并非为他自己
"A gifted man bears his gifts into the world not for himself,
而是为了身边的人
but for the people among whom he is placed.
因为天赋并不为他所有
Because the gifts are not his.
他本人就是社会所得到的馈赠"
He himself is a gift to his community."
这话是亨利·福特说的  这话对他很受用
Henry Ford said that. Did pretty well for himself.
这房间里英才云集
There are many gifted men and women in this room,
而此时此刻
and this moment,
我们自己的创造诞生了
we bring our creation into the world.
今天按下这个按钮之后
Today, with the touch of a button,
我们产生的涟漪效应
we start a ripple effect
今后将惠及本产业的好几代人
that will be felt through our community for generations.
感谢我们的工程师  为我们制造了一台原型机
Thanks to our engineers, we have a prototype.
感谢编程团队
Thanks to our programming team,
操作系统也准备就绪
we have an operating system in place.
现在  终于
And now, finally...
我们将启动我们的作品
we bring our creation to life.
-让博斯沃思来按  -对  博斯来
- Let Bosworth do it. - Yeah, let Boz.
-博斯  -博斯
- Boz! - Hey, Boz.
-博斯  博斯  -算了吧
- Boz! Boz! - Nah.
就是  博斯  来呀
Yeah. Boz, go.
博斯  上
Go Boz!
博斯去按
Boz! Do it!
嗯  来啊
Yeah, all right.
博斯  博斯  博斯  博斯
Boz, Boz, Boz, Boz...
好吧  好吧
All right. Okay.
女士们先生们
Well, ladies and gentlemen...
有时候人总得
a time comes when...
有种冒冒险  是吧
well, you gotta grab your balls and jump, am I right?
世界  你好
真是恭喜了
Hey, congratulations.
非常感谢  一会儿见
Thank you so much. I'll see you soon.
不赖嘛
Not bad.
-我们没事了吧  -嗯
- Are we good? - Yeah.
这段时间  抱歉了
Sorry about how things have been.
这个过程有时候会让我很混蛋
This process doesn't always bring out my best.
我也一样
That's true of us both.
我们该庆祝一下
We should celebrate.
明晚来吃晚饭吧
Come over for dinner tomorrow night.
你大概只见过我家车库吧
I don't think you've seen more than my garage.
嗯  好啊
Yeah, you got it.
就这么定了
It's done.
豪伊小姐
Miss Howe?
这就成了
So, that's it.
外围驱动你团队写得怎么样了
When can we expect the peripheral drivers from your team?
你今后就打算这么和我说话了吗
Is this how you're gonna talk to me from now on?
那你要我怎么和你说话
How would you like me to talk to you?
像个人那样说话
Like you're flesh and blood.
你要觉得我太公事公办  那抱歉
I'm sorry if my tone is businesslike,
但我的确是你上司
but I am your boss
而且这毕竟是工作
and this is, in fact, a business.
老天  真像活人啊
Oh, my God. So lifelike.
你是卡梅伦·豪伊吗
是的
恭喜  你是个应用程序快速开发编程员
这游戏是为你准备的  需要指示吗
好
你正站在IBM公司总部大厦里
据说有些人进来后就失踪了
你必须离开  你有一颗手榴弹
扔出
扔出手榴弹
戈登
Gordon.
我们的电脑要有性格
Our computer's gonna have a personality.
操作系统向用户提问  用户再回答
An operating system that asks you questions, you answer it back.
可以互动
You interact.
什么
What?
我需要再加384k内存
Um, I need an additional 384k of RAM.
不行
Um... no.
"不行"是什么意思
What do you mean, no?
我的意思是  绝对不行
I mean, it's completely out of the question.
操作系统像猪一样能吃
Operating systems are total pigs.
就算增加了内存
Even with the added memory,
也还是要跟其他应用抢...
you're gonna be stealing from the other applications...
-是啊  -整台电脑都会慢下来
- Yeah. - ...and slowing the entire machine down.
我知道  但是戈登  想想办法
I know, but, Gordon, figure out a way around that.
-卡梅隆  没得商量  -不...
- Cameron, it's done. - No, it's--
看看电脑吧  已经完成了
Look at it. It's done.
不  还有完成  电脑...
No, it's not done. It's-- it's--
电脑运行良好  但它需要灵魂
it works fine, but it needs a soul.
要让人们能爱上我们的电脑
It needs to be something that people can fall in love with.
我们能做到
We can do that.
我干这行15年  如果说学会了什么
Okay, if there's one thing that I've learned in the 15 years of doing this
那就是  你迟早得停止改来改去
is that at some point, you have to stop changing things.
必须满足于制造出来的东西
You have to be happy with what you've made.
你害怕了
You're scared.
我有什么好怕的
What would I be scared of?
不如造一台能给我们打手枪的电脑吧
Yeah, why don't we make the machine jerk us off, too?
我还可以在操作系统中
And I can program hundreds of commands
编写几百道命令  识别言语的地域差异
in the operating system for it to understand
好让系统理解
accounting for regional variance in speech,
针对每个用户回复编写10种回应
program 10 ways for it to respond to each.
操作系统会很健谈的
It would be conversational.
就好像在与人类交谈
It would be like speaking to a human being.
-慢点说  -你玩过《巨洞冒险》
- Slow down. - You've played "Adventure."
就像那样  但不是"我想过河"
It's like that, except instead of, "I want to cross the stream,"
而是输入"我想运行字星"
you input "I want to run WordStar."
你告诉它想让它做什么
You tell it what you want it to do.
硬件需要做什么改动
What are the hardware implications?
你和戈登谈过了吗
Have you talked to Gordon about this?
戈登太胆小了
Gordon is too scared
不敢尝试任何新的  不同寻常的东西
to try anything new or different
因为他一直失败  心里有阴影
because he's traumatized from being a loser his entire life.
我觉得这话有点夸张了
I think you might be overstating that slightly.
好吧
Okay.
看这个
See this?
这是小时候我和我爸一起做的
This I made with my dad when I was a little kid.
就是个破毛公仔
It's a stupid, stuffed thing,
但我爸操控它  还假装它说话
but my dad wiggled its head and he gave it a voice
这给了它生命
and he brought it to life.
我给它起了名字  爱上了它
I named it. I fell in love with it.
我们就是要创造这样的感情联系
This is the sort of loyalty we can create.
我们得先占有一定的市场份额
We have to get a share of the market first.
得先证明我们有能力和大对手竞争
We have to show that we can compete with the majors
然后才能继续改进
before we start changing things up.
也许第二代机器可以做这方面的尝试
Maybe for a second generation, we could do something like this.
是因为昨晚的事吗
This is because of last night.
我都没想那事
I haven't given that a second thought.
你不是说要公事公办吗
I thought you said this was a business.
没错  如果采取标准操作系统
It is. If we go with a standard operating system,
我告诉你将会如何
I know what is going to happen.
不会有什么意外或者困难
There are no surprises down that road, no pitfalls.
我们能进入计算机分销商展览
We will go to COMDEX,
摆上西尔斯的货架
we will make it into Sears,
至少能卖出十五万台
we will sell 150,000 units, guaranteed.
而你的提议保证不了任何一点
You're offering me none of that.
天哪  你说的没错
Gosh, you're right.
真不知道我怎么搞的
I don't know what's wrong with me.
大概听了你的那些漂亮话
I guess with all your grandstanding,
我真当你是个有远见的人呢
I somehow got you confused with a visionary.
原来你只是随便说说
I guess it just doesn't matter what you're saying
哗众取宠而已
as long as people are listening, right?
你这是什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
对不起
Forgive me.
我只是觉得总该有个人或物有点灵魂
I just thought something around here should have a soul.
恐怕你还得帮我梳理一遍
I may need you to walk me through this.
还是有些地方我不太懂
It's possible some of it's going over my head.
当然  没问题
Yeah, no problem.
你的话戈登都能听懂吗
Does Gordon understand everything that comes out of your mouth?
那必须是和电脑有关的
Yeah, as long as it's about computers.
他的项目进展如何
How's his project coming along?
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
他的绝密项目
His super secret project.
挺好的
It's going well.
占了他不少时间呢
It's eating up a lot of his time.
因为没有最快最小只有更快更小嘛
You know, it can always be faster, it can always be smaller.
他们已经解决了主板空间的问题
They solved the real estate problem, though.
你帮忙了吧
Did you help them with that?
或许吧
Maybe.
怎么解决的
What was the solve?
主板双面都装芯片
Chips on both sides of the board.
就这么简单
So simple.
看来你不光是我一个人的秘密武器啊
I guess you're everyone's secret weapon, huh?
绝密武器
Super secret.
说到这个
Speaking of,
公司那边需要人去介绍一下工作
corporate's gonna want a presentation of this work.
我需要你帮忙
I'm gonna need you by my side.
你能来吗
Would you be up for that?
出趟差
A little business trip?
当然能
Of course.
太好了
Good.
嗯  太好了
Yes, good.
卡梅伦跟你说了她关于操作系统的金点子了吗
Cameron tell you her bright idea about the operating system?
简直疯了  是吧
It's insane, right?
你肯定拒绝她了吧
I trust that you told her no.
你跟她说了不予考虑了吧
Tell me you told her it was out of the question.
我不知道  这也许是个好主意
I don't know. She might be onto something.
-这点子很独特  -独特
- It's certainly unique. - "Unique"?
三个月前你可没在白板上写"独特"这俩字
You didn't write "Unique" On the board three months ago.
-没准该写上  -你写的是更快  更便宜
- Maybe I should have. - You wrote "Faster," You wrote "Cheaper."
而且重点不在这儿
Anyway, that's not the point.
你知道这要占用多少主板空间吗
Do you know how much real estate that would take?
我得重新规划整个主板的布局
I'd have to rethink the entire layout of the board.
伟大就得付出代价  对吧
Greatness comes at a price, no?
没错  代价我已经付了
Yeah, and I've paid that price.
你知道我有多少个晚上没哄女儿睡觉了吗
Do you know how many nights I've missed putting my kids to bed?
你知道我在这儿熬了多少个通宵吗
You know how many all-nighters I've spent here?
你对我提出了要求  我也做到了
You asked me to do something and I did it.
本来是不可能的事  我也做到了
It was impossible and I did it anyway.
这只是个思想实验  我还在考虑
It's a thought experiment. And I'm considering it.
别  别去考虑
Well, don't. Just don't consider it.
我想考虑什么就考虑什么
I'm gonna do whatever I want to do
我让你做什么你就做什么
and you're gonna do whatever I tell you to do
你我之间的关系就是这样的
because that's the way this relationship works.
然后乔告诉我他真的在考虑
And Joe tells me he's actually considering it.
你不能再改了  现在已经很完美了
You can't change it. It's a thing of beauty.
我不清楚  没准他说得对呢
I don't know. Maybe he's right.
不  戈登  你的电脑很完美
No, Gordon, you built a beautiful machine.
你得维护自己的作品
You have to stand up for it.
乔·麦克米伦就是一混蛋
Joe MacMillan's an asshole.
他对你的工作毫不了解
He doesn't know a fraction of what you do
根本不知道什么叫好电脑
about what makes a good computer.
老爸  飓风要来了吗
Daddy, is the hurricane gonna come?
不会  这边可能会刮大风  下点雨
No, no, no, no. We might get a big storm, some rain,
但是飓风到不了这儿的
but the hurricane can't reach us here.
休斯顿大概会被吹惨了  但是
Houston might get walloped, but--
咱这儿很安全  去玩吧
We're safe here. You guys go play.
你买了那个什么了吗
Oh, hey, did you get the you-know-what?
-什么  -那个椰菜...
- What's that? - The Cabbage...
什么椰菜
Did I get cabbage?
不是  是那个
No, the--
椰菜娃娃
the Cabbage Patch Kid.
啊买了  我放在办公室了
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. I left it at the office.
我不想让琼妮找到  她老是到处乱翻
I didn't want Joanie to find it. She snoops, you know?
对了  最糟糕的是
Anyway, sort of the worst part of it is--
你要记住  你是爱我的
please keep in mind that you love me when I tell you this,
在我俩吵架之前
but before everything went down,
我请乔来吃晚饭了
I invited Joe for dinner tomorrow.
-来家里吗  -我当时觉得这主意挺好
- Dinner here? - I know, it felt like the right thing to do.
能让我俩更和睦点
You know? Smooth things over.
那你觉得这个想法
Well, do you think this idea
真会毁了你的成果吗
could really compromise what you've done?
会
Yeah.
那你得尽全力改变他的想法
Well, you have to do whatever you can to change his mind.
哪怕得请他来吃饭
Even if that means inviting him into our home.
这是你的机器  戈登  别让他毁了
It's your machine, Gordon. Don't let him ruin it.
嗯
Yeah.
怎么了这是
So, what's going on in there?
出什么问题了
Is something wrong?
我卡壳了
I'm stuck.
进来吧
Come in.
要搭车吗
Hey, you need a ride to work?
不用  我得写完
Uh, no, I'm on a roll.
怎么了
What?
你测试驱动了吗
Hey, did you start the tests on those drivers?
没  程序员还没给我
No, I'm waiting for the coders to give them to me.
-莱夫  -我知道  莱夫
- Lev. - Yeah, I know. Lev.
我想问驱动什么时候能完成
Listen, I was wondering when we were gonna get some of the drivers.
得尽快进行端到端测试
We need to start end-to-end testing as soon as possible.
我在写操作系统扩展
I'm working on the OS expansion.
什么  谁让你干这个的
What? Who told you to work on that?
卡梅伦
Cameron did.
乔也同意了吗
Did Joe approve that?
你接着写驱动
Go back to working on the driver, okay?
老大是我  不是卡梅伦
I'm the boss, not Cameron.
卡梅伦负责软件部分
Well, Cameron's in charge of software.
我负责不让别人干傻事
Well, I'm in charge of stopping idiotic things from happening.
你可以相信我
And you can trust me.
我不是靠睡产品经理得逞的
I'm not screwing the product manager to get my way.
什么
What?
莱夫  接着写驱动  好吗
Lev, just go back to working on the driver, okay?
我来解决
I'll straighten this out.
戈登  你妻子来电话
Gordon, your wife called.
她要我提醒你那个
She wanted me to remind you about the...
椰菜娃娃
The Cabbage Patch.
附近有玩具店吗
Do you know of a toy store nearby?
帮我找一找呗  黛比
Well, can you find one, Debbie?
-好的  -太好了
- Yes. - That'd be great.
玩具世界
椰菜娃娃售罄
不要
No...!
-该死的  -哥们  你好啊
- Son of a bitch. - Hey, pal. Hey there.
你不会是想买椰菜娃娃吧
You ain't looking for a Cabbage Patch by any chance?
-没错  -我有一个
- Yeah. Yeah, I am. - I got one.
这些混蛋高价卖我80块
I paid 80 bucks for it 'cause these jerks marked it up
就因为是最后一个
'cause it was the last one.
现在他们又不让我退
And now they won't let me return it.
-我买了  -真的吗
- I'll take it. - Honestly?
-真的  -你真是我的救世主
- Yeah, yeah. - Oh, you're a lifesaver.
-我买了  -谢谢  就在这儿
- Yeah, yeah. - Thank you. It's right here.
你可帮了我大忙
You are really saving my butt.
彼此彼此  相信我
Likewise, believe me.
现在我能回家求我老婆上床了
All right, well, now I might go home and beg the wife for sex.
或许还能成功呢
Probably get some, too.
祝你好运
Well, good luck.
不
No.
No!
模块弄得怎么样了
Hey, where are you with that module?
-你逗我呢  -怎么了
- Are you kidding me? - What?
戈登让我们所有人去写驱动
Gordon retasked us all with drivers.
你们总改变指示  烦死了
You keep changing directions on us. This sucks.
想好到底要我们做什么  我们会照做的  天呐
Just figure out what you want us to do and we'll do it, Jesus.
把所有程序员叫到我办公室来
Get all the coders in my office.
马上
Now.
我不知道别人跟你们说了什么
I don't know what anyone else has told you,
但我是你们的经理  你们听我的指示  好吗
but I'm your manager. You take instructions from me, okay?
别人也都这么说
That's what everyone else is saying.
他们错了  好吗
Well, they're wrong, okay?
今天就把操作系统的模块做出来
I need that module for the OS and I need it today.
还有问题吗
Any questions?
我有个问题  你在上乔·麦克米伦吗
I got a question. Are you banging Joe MacMillan?
我傻到以为一个玩具店
Oh, yeah, I'm stupid for thinking a toy store
会卖世界上最流行的玩具
might carry the world's most popular toy.
喂
Hello?
黛比
Debbie!
-找到了吗  -还没呢
- Any luck? - Not yet!
我要找一个椰菜娃娃
Uh, yes, I'm looking for a Cabbage Patch Kid.
是吗
You do?
真的吗
Uh, really?
你能先留住它吗
C-can you put it on hold?
我现在就去
No, I will come right now.
别卖掉那个椰菜娃娃
Look, do not sell that Cabbage Patch.
喂
Hello?
-戈登  -什么
- Gordon? - What?
你昨晚太销魂了
You were incredible last night.
我绝不会跟她上床的  好吗
I-- I would never, okay?
你们见过唐娜的  对吧
Y-y-you guys know Donna, right?
乔  很高兴这么大雨你还能来赴约
Joe, glad you could make it in this downpour.
快请进  戈登还没回来
Oh, come in. Gordon's not back yet, but
但他应该马上就到了
he should be here soon.
66年的波尔多葡萄酒  值得一品
Uh, '66 Bordeaux. Really interesting.
谢谢  你真周到
Thank you. How thoughtful.
你认识琼妮和海莉吧
You know Joanie and Haley, right?
姑娘们  打招呼  这是乔  爸爸的同事
Girls, say hi. This is Joe, Daddy's work friend.
-乔  你好  -晚上好
- Hi, Joe. - Evening.
工作怎么样
So, how's everything going at work?
戈登跟我说一切进展顺利
Gordon tells me things are progressing nicely.
嗯  挺顺利的
Yeah, moving right along.
你坐的那只鞋可是从意大利来的呢
That shoe you're sitting on comes all the way from Italy.
那是哪里
Where's that?
很远的地方
Far away from here.
戈登应该就快回来了
Gordon should be back any minute.
我是不是都说过了
Did I say that already?
今晚  加尔维斯顿又将遭遇强飓风
Galveston is once again braced for a major hurricane tonight.
风速超过时速110英里
Winds exceeding 110 miles per hour...
-你去哪  -回家
- Where are you going? - Home.
得了  外面雨那么大
Oh, come on. It's pissing rain out there.
来跟我喝杯酒
Come have a drink with me.
来吧  我给你调卡迪夫特色酒
Come on, I'll make you a Cardiff Special.
我不接受拒绝
I'm not taking no for an answer.
赶快点  丫头
Come on, shake it, kid.
一切还好吧
Hope everything's all right.
没事的  就我对我丈夫的了解
No, everything's fine. If I know my husband,
他正在外面疯子似的到处跑
he's out right now running around frantically,
找椰菜娃娃呢
trying to find a Cabbage Patch Kid.
姑娘们  别去折腾他了
Oh, girls, would you leave him alone, please?
-你多大了  -35  怎么了
- How old are you? - I'm 35, why?
不知道  我六岁
I don't know. I'm six.
行了  你们想搭城堡吗
Hey, okay, okay. What about a fort?
-好  -要搭城堡吗
- Okay. - Would you like to build a fort?
好嘞
All right, uh...
你们知道哪有毯子吗
Do you girls know if we can find any blankets?
-好  -把那把椅子转过来
- Okay. - Okay, let's turn that chair around.
好
Okay.
好嘞
Here we go.
行了  都进去
All right, everyone in.
来  都进来  都进来
Come on, everyone in. Everyone in.
戈登跟我说你打算
So, Gordon tells me you're thinking of
对操作系统进行试验性的改进
doing something experimental with the OS?
我在考虑
I'm considering it.
事实上  我就是想做件大事
The truth is, I just want to do something great.
那么折磨卡梅伦算什么
How did torturing Cameron fit into that?
那事我很后悔
I regret that...
但我是为了让世人注意我们
but it was about getting the world's attention.
我还想成功
I guess I also want to do something successful.
那你就该听戈登的
Well, then you should listen to Gordon.
他真的很天才
He's actually a genius.
要不我干吗选他啊
Why do you think I chose him?
你了解对手
You know the competition.
想要挤进他们的市场
The only way to cut into their market share is
就得质量比他们好或价格比他们低  或都做到
by doing what they do better or cheaper or both,
这你是能做到的  只要你不再做改动
and you can do that if you stick with what you've got.
独创性也很重要  不是吗
There's something to be said for ingenuity, no?
当然了  我就是这意思
Well, sure. Exactly. That's what I'm saying.
你们的机器很有独创性
There's ingenuity in there.
这台机器你都看了几个月了
You've been sitting with this machine for a few months now.
有时候人会看不出
It's easy to lose sight of what's great
眼前的东西有多伟大  因为太习惯成自然
when it's right in front of you. You get used to it.
你们造的电脑简直是艺术品
The computer you two built is a work of art,
不止如此  还能热卖
and not only that, it'll sell.
你可以相信你最初的设想
So you can believe in your original vision.
你促成了这一切
You made it all happen.
老天爷啊
Whew, God Alfrighty.
天呐  下得真大
Jeez, it's coming down now.
下午在大办公室闹的那是哪一出
What was that dustup in the bullpen this afternoon?
说来话长
It's a long story.
我有的是时间
Yeah, well, I got nothing but time.
克拉克啊
Clark, huh?
戈登挺好的
Gordon is good.
他真的很好
He's really good.
但戈登想建的电脑
But Gordon wants to build a computer
是一台让电脑行业赞叹的电脑
that'll impress all the other people who build computers.
而我想建一台让普通人
I want to build something for people who
那些从未想过自己想要电脑的人
never thought they'd want a computer,
对电脑毫不了解的人喜欢的电脑
who don't know anything about them.
我想为你这样的人建一台电脑
I want to build a computer for you.
喂喂  我还是了解电脑的
Hey, now. I know my way around a damn computer.
你还垫尿布的时候我就入行了  丫头
I've been in this business since before you were in diapers, kid.
行啦  你懂我的意思
All right. You know what I mean.
我想建一台能让人爱上的电脑
I want to build something that makes people fall in love.
你怎么爱上电脑的
How'd you fall in love?
电脑俱乐部
Computer Club.
我初中的时候朋友不多
I didn't have a ton of friends in junior high.
令人震惊
Oh, I am shocked by that.
嗯
Yeah.
有一天午餐的时候  我躲在一间教室里
So, yeah, I was hiding out in a classroom at lunch
然后电脑俱乐部进来了
and the Computer Club came in.
我就装作我本来就该在那儿
I just pretended I was there on purpose.
门罗老师教我们BASIC语言
Mr. Monroe taught us BASIC and
那感觉简直犹如沙漠中找到甘泉
it was like finding water in the middle of the desert.
我第一次知道要如何交流
For the first time, I knew how to talk to something.
我终于掌握合适的语言了
I finally had the right language.
我们这不聊得挺好
You're talking just fine now.
我喝醉了嘛
I'm drunk.
听我说
Listen, now, the--
今天的那出闹剧
the theatrics out there today.
你要小心点  卡梅
Be more careful, Cam.
我不小了  我能照顾好自己
I'm a big girl. I can take care of myself.
我知道  这还用说吗  但是...
Oh, hell, I know that. That's plain as day. It's just...
这里的一些人
Some of the people around here,
不管他们怎么说  甚至怎么想
no matter what they say, or even what they think--
他们始终有点希望你搞砸
part of them wants to see you shit the bed on this thing.
为什么
Why's that?
因为你是未来
'Cause you're the future.
没什么比这更让人害怕的了
Ain't nothing scarier than that.
我小时候  大暴风雨来袭时
When I was little, any time there was a big storm,
我爸会带我们出去
my dad would take us out in it
让我知道这没什么好怕的
to show me there was nothing to be afraid of.
之后一个邻居的孩子被倒下的树压在了下面
Then a kid in our neighborhood got pinned under a fallen tree
他就不再那么做了
and so he stopped doing that.
那时候做父母好不一样啊
I feel like parenting used to be different.
我妈以前会带我登上
My mom used to take me up to the
我们家的屋顶看星星
roof of our old Victorian to look at the stars.
我们居然能活到今天真是奇迹
That any of us survived is a miracle.
好了  没事的
Hey, hey, it's okay.
你们怕飓风吗
You afraid of the hurricane?
但你们有飓风控制器啊
But you've got hurricane zappers right here.
你们不知道这是什么吗  就这个啊
You don't know about hurricane zappers? Oh, yeah, these.
把这个指向风暴  它就伤不到你了
Just point them at the storm and it can't hurt you.
真的  试试吧
Here, I'm telling you the truth. Give it a shot.
在屋里照就行吗
It'll work through the roof?
嗯  大点的飓风你就得去屋外了
Oh, yeah. A bigger storm, you might need to go outside.
不过这种小风暴  在屋里就行
But a little storm like this, through the roof should be fine.
-去试试吧  -瞧他们
- Let's try it. - There they go.
椰菜娃娃
不行啊
It's not working.
我试试行吗
Mind if I give it a shot?
风暴太大了  你得出去
It's a big storm. You have to do it outside.
-不  亲爱的  -大概让你说中了
- No, sweetheart... - You're probably right.
大概真是这样
You're probably right.
-乔  你不用的...  -行了  跟我来
- Joe, you don't have to... - Okay, follow me.
真的
You really don't have to.
-小心  别伤到她  -她
- Be careful, don't let her get hurt. - Her?
-安娜塔西亚  -你给它起名了
- Anastasia. - You named it.
我的叫莎尔姬
Mine is Sharky.
她们是你的朋友吗
And they're your friends?
我一定小心
I promise to be very careful.
看着
Okay, watch.
-他干什么呢  -我们去看看吧
- What's he doing? - Let's go see.
在外面效果好多了
It works a lot better outside.
好了  好了
OK. All right, all right.
-给你  -谢谢
- Here you go. - Oh, thanks.
-戈登  -爸爸
- Gordon! - Daddy!
我们担心死你了  你没事吧
We were worried about you. Are you all right?
嗯  没事  抱歉我这么晚才回来
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm so sorry I'm so late.
你怎么了
What happened to you?
谢谢你留到现在  乔  多谢了
Oh, thanks for sticking around, Joe. I appreciate it.
没事
It's no problem.
我们吃吧  你们吃了吗
Should we eat? Did you guys eat?
我还是走吧  不打扰你们了
I should go, leave you guys alone.
反正风暴也要散了
Storm's clearing up anyway.
那个...
Well...
乔  我还要跟你谈谈呢
Joe, I need to talk to you.
戈登  明天谈吧
Oh, no, Gordon, you can talk tomorrow.
谢谢邀请我来
Hey, thanks for inviting me.
明天见
Uh, I'll see you tomorrow.
-再见了  姑娘们  -再见
- Bye, girls. - Bye.
你没事吧
Hey, are you okay?
嗯
Uh, yeah, yeah.
干什么
What do you want?
你有什么人吗
Do you have anybody?
什么
What are you talking about?
如果你被困在飓风里
If you got stuck in a hurricane,
你有可以求助的人吗
do you have anybody you would call?
我没有
I don't.
给我看看你写的东西
Show me what you've been working on.
按回车
Press "Enter."
有点礼貌啊  电脑跟你说话呢
Don't be rude. Computer's talking to you.
回答他
Answer it.
乔·麦克米伦
你是谁
你在耍我吗
You messing with me?
目前只辨认名字
Well, it only does first names right now.
你是谁
乔
你好  乔  你想做什么
我小时候  我妈妈会带我
When I was a kid, my mom used to take me
上屋顶看星星
up to the roof to look at the stars.
她很疯狂
She was wild and...
在乱嗑药
experimented with drugs.
有一次  她没抓住我
One time, she let go of my hand
我坠下三层楼
and I fell three stories
落在前院的栅栏上
and landed on a fence in the front yard.
接下来两年我差不多一直躺在医院里
I spent most of the next two years in a hospital bed.
卡梅伦
Cameron?
怎么
Yeah?
这感觉真好
This is really good.
人人影视
倾情奉献
翻译
潇湘月影
小酸奶!
翻译
某豚
冬麟   木浅薰
翻译
磁芯章鱼X
小花豆
翻译
somehacker
草草卖安利
时间轴
Kallen 芒果树叶
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第一季
第六集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌